# **Robinson Simon**

12386 Criollo Rd. Spring Hill, FL 34610 PHONE (949) 633-0225 | E-MAIL robsimon01@gmail.com | WEBSITE robasimon.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer and United States Air Force Veteran with 12 years of work experience. Skilled in critical thinking, communication, and decision-making; exceptional at remaining calm under extreme pressure. Seeking to use acquired knowledge and skills to obtain career in the software engineering field. I am interested in cloud services and full-stack development.

## **SKILLS**

Platforms/Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/10, Android, Debian, iOS, Mac OS X, Linux, UNIX,

Ubuntu

Programming: C++, C, Python , Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Technologies/Environment: Docker, Git, GitLab, GitHub, JSON, Microsoft Access, Microsoft Office,

Microsoft .NET Framework, MobaXterm, Postman, PostgreSQL, React,

Redux, Visual Studio, VS Code

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer, CAE USA

Tampa, FL

Intern

July 2020 – Present

- Functioned as part of research and development team to produce realistic aircraft simulator.
- Integrated speech recognition using RASA engine to provide realistic ATC conversations with pilots.
- Created scripted scenarios for simulation.
- Produced updates and new implementations for project utilizing Agile development and Jira task management systems.
- Collaborated with project managers, tech leads, and team members in bi-weekly meetings discussing current sprint responsibilities.
- Experienced in remote work environment.

## Software Engineer, SOFWERX

Tampa, FL

Intern

Jan 2020 – Aug 2020

- Produced machine learning component for Zero Trust Network concept to improve speed throughout network.
- Created scripts to simplify and automate tasks.
- Worked with peer development team on analysis, design, and implementation of web app and web service using various programming languages.
- Built software testing schemes; wrote unit tests; verified, demonstrated, and documented the design.
- Developed solutions and created products for both front-end and back-end utilizing various coding languages.
- Published article on ClockWerx project documenting design, implementation, and results.

### Contingency Response Group, U.S. Air Force

McGuire AFB, NJ

Continency ATC/Trainer

August 2014- November 2017

- Squadron training manager maintaining and ensuring 130+ employee training for worldwide deployment.
- Certified Landing Zone Safety Officer for military aircraft in austere environments.
- Squadron facility manager maintaining and organizing building maintenance including lighting, ceiling tiles, heat, air conditioning, and computers for over forty-five people.

• Maintained Secret Security Clearance.

Air Traffic Control, U.S. Air Force

McGuire AFB, NJ

Journeyman/Trainer

November 2011- November 2017

- Directed ground and air traffic to ensure safe facility operations. Ensured the separation of aircraft and issuance of safety alerts for 45k+ yearly operations.
- Facilitated numerous inflight and ground emergency situations saving lives and millions of dollars in property.
- Completed and maintained Air Traffic Control skills and training certifications outlined by Federal Aviation Administration and McGuire Air Force Base regulations.
- Trained several apprentices by completing weekly evaluations and assessments that included daily question and answer sessions, simulator, and live training.
- Applied effective and efficient flow of communication between multiple controllers and facilities
  ensuring utilization of universal phraseology, flight strip markings, and priority of transmissions as
  outlined in the FAA JO 7110.65V.

### **EDUCATION**

University of South Florida

Tampa, FL Expected Dec 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

**GPA: 3.86** 

Hillsborough Community College Associate of Arts in Computer Science Tampa, FL 2018

# **PROJECTS**

- Developed mobile selling app (Flip Phone) built and designed Android app utilizing Firebase database. Allows users to register, sell smart phone devices, on-screen guided picture taking, complete CRUD implementation.
- Website built and styled modern professional website utilizing JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. www.github.com/robasimon
- Developed scheduling app CRUD implementation. Allows users to sign up, add employees and shifts to database. Displays current shifts on calendar and on main screen.

# HONORS & AWARDS

First recipient of the Norman N. Blankenship Family Scholarship at the University of South Florida. Dean's list.

United States Air Force -

AF Outstanding Unit Award with 2 Oak Leaf Clusters, AF Good Conduct Medal, National Defense Service Medal, Global War on Terrorism Expeditionary Medal, Global War on Terrorism Service Medal, Air Force Expeditionary Service Ribbon with Gold Border with 1 Oak Leaf Cluster, AF Longevity Service, AF Training Ribbon.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- https://sofwerx.github.io/docs/ZeroTrustNetwork.pdf
- <a href="https://sofwerx.github.io/docs/IRSendValidation.pdf">https://sofwerx.github.io/docs/IRSendValidation.pdf</a>